Aasiya Fazal

UI / UX Designer



Design Skills

User Interviews and Surveys

Workshop Facilitation

User Journey Mapping

User Personas

User Testing

UI / Visual Design

User Research and Competitor Analysis

Profile

I am a UI/UX Designer passionate about the key role of design in bridging the gap between technology's potential to make the world a better place and the realisation of this in the form of better health, wellbeing and social mobility. I have a portfolio of six projects, my own website I designed and developed from scratch using CSS, HTML and JavaScript, as well as, design experience within the NHS, Warwick University, My Local Chemist, Cancer Research UK and Healum. With my previous experience spanning across service design, project management, consulting, data analytics, operational improvement and team leadership, I have a versatile skillset to complement my UI/UX design skills.

Education

Apr 2023 - May 2023

The Knowledge Academy

Agile Project Management Foundation & Practitioner (AgilePM®) and Scrum Master Certification

June 2020 - Feb 2023

CareerFoundry

Birmingham University

UX/UI course including cross platform design and web development, during which <u>4 projects</u> were completed.

Sept 2019 - Oct 2021

Elizabeth Garrett Anderson Postgraduate Diploma in Health Leadership, **Distinction**.

Oct 2013 - June 2017

Durham University

Bachelor of Science in Business, Computer Science and Economics, First Class Honours.

Skills



MURAL

WORDPRESS

JS

JAVASCRIPT



MIRO

HTML

5

HTML

PYTHON











SQL

Project Management Skills

Layout, Typography and Style Guides

Requirements and User Stories

Wireframing and Prototyping

Agile DSDM **Process Flow Mapping** Stakeholder Management

Developing Business Cases and SOPs Project Timelines **Project Progress Tracking**

Data Analysis Skills

Risk Management

Intermediate SQL Tableau Dashboards Advanced Microsoft Excel PowerQuery

Employment

Sept 2023 - Present

Innovation Design Facilitator at Health and Wellbeing Innovation Network, Warwick University (Part Time)

- Designed and conducted a user discovery exercise for the UHUK conference, which involved me creating an interactive survey and a Tableau dashboard which displayed real time insights from this.
- Currently redesigning our team's website using WordPress which has involved using content prioritisation techniques.
- Design and facilitate innovation workshops with clients using techniques ranging from Design thinking, Lean and Systems Thinking.
- · Work with external organisations to build product pipelines and roadmaps with a view to testing, validating and iterating solutions for the healthcare market.

Aug 2023 - Present

UX/UI Intern at My Local Chemist (Part Time)

- Worked with key stakeholders to design a <u>high fidelity prototype</u> for a stock control app within their company.
- To evaluate the opportunity to commercialise this product, I led a user discovery exercise which involved having a stand at The Pharmacy Show 2023 and gathering insights from pharmacy chain owners.
- Currently working on a project to design a delivery app which will be used across the company's chain of pharmacies to increase efficiencies and improve patient experience.

Oct 2021 - May 2022

Oncology Service Design / Improvement Manager at Royal Orthopaedic Hospital NHS Foundation Trust

- Achieved improvements to patient experience along the cancer pathway through: supporting effective collaboration between staff, facilitating co-creation of process changes and coordinating the implementation of iterative changes.
- Successfully led efforts to clear the significant backlog of over 1000 clinical letters discovered upon commencing my role. This was achieved through engaging all key stakeholders to map out the process and its bottlenecks, facilitating discussions around solutions and coordinating implementation of improvements. Letter turnaround time reduced from over 20 days in October 2021 to 7-10 days by March 2022.
- Directly managed a total of eleven staff and recruited to multiple vacancies within the team.

June 2021 - Sept 2021

User Experience Intern at Healum

- Worked within an agile environment carrying out user testing with patients and health and social care professionals on version 1 of Healum's app and communicated findings at regular intervals to the product manager, software engineers and project manager.
- Led user research activities which informed how their health and wellbeing app could be tailored better towards people with diabetes and obesity. User research activities included secondary research, planning and conducting user interviews and focus groups.
- A final report was produced including key themes and user stories for proposed new features. This research inspired the app design for WEIInUS, one of the projects within my course portfolio, for which I produced user flows, low, mid and high fidelity wireframes, a style guide and interactive iOS and Android prototypes.

Sept 2019 - June 2021

Service Design / Integration Manager at NHS Leadership Academy

- Organised and facilitated workshops and process mapping activities between key health and social care stakeholders using Miro, Mural and Figma. This enabled them to work collaboratively and improve on 60 existing services to enhance patient experience along the hospital discharge pathway.
- Successfully coordinated user discovery activities with over 400 individuals aged 60+ to gain an in depth picture of digital literacy in our local area during COVID. This involved creating a telephone survey, coordinating its completion and producing an infographic which I presented at Board level.
- Played an instrumental role in the design and implementation of a new primary care service called the Healthy Ageing Coordinator service. This involved production of induction materials and SOPs for new staff, as well as, developing promotional posters, a video and patient success stories to promote the value of the service.

July 2019 - Aug 2019

Summer Intern in Technology at Cancer Research UK

- My first insight into a UI/UX career, during which I received an Employee Appreciation for facilitating user lab testing on an Alexa quiz prototype.
- Led a project to rejuvenate CRUK's Technology recruitment page. This involved: leading workshops around content prioritisation, interviewing employees, using storytelling techniques and copywriting.
- Successfully led an Afternoon Light Bites event which made a £400 profit. This involved securing food donations from high profile brands and innovative marketing using QR codes.
- Co-created sections of a best practice catalogue for Technology employees through facilitating workshops with Technology leads from each team in the department.

Oct 2017 - June 2019

Technology Associate at KPMG

- Received four Encore Awards for my commitment to delivering high quality work and consistently excelling at fulfilling an experienced professional role on projects. These projects typically involved: managing various stakeholder relationships,
- process mapping, conducting stakeholder interviews and writing reports or presentations. My achievements included: conducting a thematic analysis of an IT Customer Satisfaction survey for a client and presenting this to their IT Leadership team, supporting an IT control redesign project in Amsterdam for one of the largest

travel companies in the world and creating a project status dashboard for a client under a pressurised deadline.